Guide to the Breed Collection of Maps, Documents, and Prints, 1545-1973
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
- MAPS — EUROPE — GERMANY
  - Accoratiffina Germaniae tabula denuo in lucem edita a Iusto Danckerts [Justus Danckerts, 1635-1701], Amstelodami, undated; (20.5 x 24.25 | tinted) (139 (Map Case Drawer 14))
  - Hassia svperior et Mogvntinvs archiepiscopatvs, undated; (20 x 24 | tinted) (140 (Map Case Drawer 14))
    — Text on verso (pages 281-282).
  - Magdeburgensis Archiepiscopatvs, Amsteloedami, G. Blaeu [Willem (Janszoon?) Blaeu] excudebat, undated; (20 x 24 | tinted and decorated) (141 (Map Case Drawer 14))
    — Text in Latin on verso (pages 221-222): "Archiepiscop. Magdebvrgensis."
  - Mansfeldia Comitatvs, Auctore Tilemanno Stella Sig. Apud Guiljelm. Blaeu [Willem (Janszoon?) Blaeu], undated; (20 x 24 | tinted) (142 (Map Case Drawer 14))
    — Text in Latin on verso (pages 113-114): "Mansfeldia Comitatvs."
  - Marca Brandenbvrgensis and Pomerania, undated; (10 x 13.75 | black and white with red lineation) (143 (Box 1))
    — Text on verso (page or number 19).
    — Text on verso (pages 129-130).
  - Marchionatus Brandenburgisi pars, quae Marchia Vetus, vulgo Altemarck, dicitur, undated; (20 x 24 | tinted) (144 (Map Case Drawer 14))
  - Marchionatus Brandenburgici partes duae, Nova Marchia et Uckerana, Auctore Osao Joannis Gotho, Gustovo Magni cosmographo, undated; (20 x 24 | tinted) (145 (Map Case Drawer 14))
    — Text on verso (pages 137-138).
  - Marchionatvs Brandenburgici partes duae, Ruppin Comitatus and Prignits Reguincula, Auth. Olao Iohannis Gotho, Gustavo Magno cosm, undated; (20 x 24 | tinted) (146 (Map Case Drawer 14))
    — Text on verso (page 139).
  - Oldenbvrg comitatvs, Amstelodami, Guiljelm. Blaeuw [Willem (Janszoon?) Blaeu] excudit, undated; (20 x 24 | tinted) (147 (Map Case Drawer 14))
    — Text on verso (pages 245-246).
  - Palatinatvs Bavariae, Amsterdami, Excudit Guiljelmus Blaeuw [Willem (Janszoon?) Blaeu], undated; (20 x 24 | tinted) (148 (Map Case Drawer 14))
    — Text on verso (pages 97-98).
  - Principatus Anhaltinus, undated; (20 x 24 | tinted and decorated) (149 (Map Case Drawer 14))
    — Text in Latin on verso (pages 115-116): "Principatvs Anhaltinvs."
  - S.R.I. Circulus Rhenanus Superior... Norimbergae, Ioh. Baptistae Homanni [Johann Baptist Homann, 1663-1724], undated; (20.5 x 24.5 | tinted) (150 (Map Case Drawer 14))
  - Saltzburg Archiepiscopatus, et Carinthia Ducatus, Auct. Ger. Mercatore. Amsterdami, apud Guiljelmum Blaeu [Willem (Janszoon?) Blaeu], undated; (20 x 24 | tinted) (151 (Map Case Drawer 14))
    — Text on verso (pages 81-82).
  - Serenisfimo Principi ac Domino, Domino Ernesto Frierico... Ejusdem Principatus Saxo-Hildurghusian, Norimbergae, Ionnes Bapt. Homann [Johann Baptist Homann, 1663-1724], 1710; (22.5 x 25.5 | tinted and decorated) (152 (Map Case Drawer 14))
  - Saxonia superior, cum Lusatia et Misnia, undated; (20 x 24.25 | tinted) (153 (Map Case Drawer 14))
    — Praga at central lower edge.
    — Text on verso (pages 101-102).
  - Silesia Inferior.. ., a Jona Sculteto, Sprotta-Silensio Joh. et corn. Blaeu [Willem (Janszoon?) Blaeu] excud., undated; (20 x 24 | tinted and decorated) (154 (Map Case Drawer 14))
    — Text in Latin on verso (pages 55-56): "Silesia Inferior."
  - Terra Advocatorum vulgo Voightland, Descripta ab Olao Ioannis Gotho, Amsterdam, Blaeu [Willem (Janszoon?) Blaeu], undated; (20 x 24 | tinted) (155 (Map Case Drawer 14))
    — Text on verso (pages 105-106).
  - Territorii Novoforensis in Superiore Palatinatu accurata descriptio, Auctore Nicolao Rittershusio D., undated; (16 x 24 | tinted; was mended at center, but is separating again) (156 (Map Case Drawer 14))
    — Text on verso (pages 99-100).
  - Territorii Novaforensis in Superior Palatinatu, accurata descriptio, Auct. Nicolao Rittershusio D., undated; (22 x 26 | tinted) (157 (Map Case Drawer 14))
  - Theatrm Belli Rhenani... Norimbergae, Ioan. Baptista Homan [Johann Baptist Homann, 1663-1724], [1702?]; (20 x 24 | tinted) (158 (Map Case Drawer 14))
  - Thvringia, Comitatuum Prouincialium Romani Imperii secunda.. ., Iohan busemecher excudit Coloniae, 1603; (10.25 x 12.25 | black and white with red lineation) (159 (Box 1))
    — Text on verso (page or number 32).
  - Waldeck Comitatus, Amsterdami, apud Guiljelmum Blaeu [Willem (Janszoon?) Blaeu], undated; (20.25 x 24 | tinted and decorated) (160 (Map Case Drawer 14))
    — Text on verso in Latin (pages 297-298): "Waldeck comitatvs."
  - Wetteravia Vulgo Die Wetteram, undated; (20 x 24 | tinted) (161 (Map Case Drawer 14))
    — Franckfurt near lower left.
    — Text on verso (pages 287-288).
  - Cartinthiae ducatus, et Goritiae Palatintus, Wolf. Lazio auctore, undated; (11 x 17 | tinted) (247 (Box 1))
    — Text on verso (page 89).
  - Nova Anhaltini Prinicpatus Tabula Autore IOH Tobia Schuchart..., MDCCX, 1710; (25.5 x 21.875 | tinted) (278 (Map Case Drawer 15))
    — Small tear, but otherwise good condition.
  - Westfalia, [Abraham Ortelius, 1527-1598], Theatro. Anversa, Plantin, 1593; (9.5 x 11.55, including matting | handcolored with inset) (289 (Box 1))
    — Numbered 44.
    — Handwritten note in pencil, "Ortelius 1593."
    — Text in Italian on verso.
  - Pomerania, [Abraham Ortelius, 1527-1598], Theatro. Anversa, Plantin, 1593; (9.5 x 11.55, including matting | handcolored with inset) (290 (Box 1))
    — Numbered 49.
  - A correct map of the North West part of Germany containing Westphalia & Lower Saxony by [Emanuel Bowen, 1693 or 1694-1767], undated; (16 x 20 | black and white) (MISSING AS OF 2019)
  - A new and correct map of the South West part of Germany, containing the Archbishopricks and Electorates of Mentz and Triers..., by [Emanuel Bowen, 1693 or 1694-1767], undated; (16 x 19.5 | black and white) (MISSING AS OF 2019)
    — One of 10 Illustrations made for Tyndal's continuation of Rapin's History of England.
- MAPS — EUROPE — GREAT BRITAIN
  - Britannia Romana, undated; (15.25 x 16.75 | black and white) (045 (Map Case Drawer 12))
  - Britannia Saxonica, undated; (15.25 x 17 | black and white) (046 (Map Case Drawer 12))
    — Note at upper left: "To be placed before the 2nd Book."
  - Cambriae Typus Auctore Humfredo Lhuydro Denbigiense Cambrobritanno, undated; (19.5 x 23 | tinted and decorated) (047 (Map Case Drawer 12))
    — Wales
    — Text in French on verso: "La IV table d' Angleterre, laquelle contient La Cambrie ov Wallie."
  - Comitatus Rotelandiae [Rutlandshire] tabula nova & aucta, Sold by A. Swale, A. Churchil and Partners, [1690]; (15 x 17.5 | black and white) (048 (Map Case Drawer 12))
    — Section of England bounded by Leicestershire, Northamptonshire and Lincolnshire.
  - Devonshire, by Robert Morden, Sold by Abel Swale Awnsham & Iohn Churchil, [1690]; (17.5 x 15.5 | tinted) (049 (Map Case Drawer 12))
  - Devonshire, by Robert Morden, Sold by Abel Swale Awnsham & Iohn Churchil, [1690]; (17.5 x 15.5 | black and white) (050 (Map Case Drawer 12))
  - Devonshire, by Robert Morden, Sold by Abel Swale Awnsham & Iohn Churchil, [1690]; (17.5 x 15.5 | black and white) (051 (Map Case Drawer 12))
  - Eboracum, Lincolnia, Derbia, Staffordia, Notinghamia, Lecestria, Rutlandia, et Norfolcia, Per Gerardum Mercatorem..., [1595]; (15.5 x 20.5 | tinted) (052 (Map Case Drawer 13))
    — Text in Latin on verso: "Angeliae... "
  - Lecestriae Rutlandiaeq. Comitatuum delineatio, printed and sold by P. Stent, 1602; (18 x 22 | black and white) (053 (Map Case Drawer 13))
  - A New Map of Great Britain. According to the Newest and most exact observations by Herman Moll Geographer, undated; (24.5 x 40.5 | tinted; once folded in quarters, now in 3 pieces; margins badly torn with small pieces missing) (162 (Map Case Drawer 14))
    — Inset: Shetland Isles.
  - Suthsexia vermacule Sussex, Amstelodami, apud Gerardum Valk et Petrum Schenk, [1630]; (22 x 25.75 | tinted) (163 (Map Case Drawer 14))
  - Rutlandia Comitatus. Rutlandshire, [1646]; (20 x 23.75 | tinted and decorated in bright colors including a pastoral scene and coats of arms) (164 (Map Case Drawer 14))
    — Text in Latin on verso (p.285-286): "... Rvtland-shire/Leicester-shire."
  - A general Plott and description of the Fennes and surounded grounds in the sixe Counties of Norfolke, Suffolke, Cambridge, with in the Isle of Ely, Huntington, Northampton and Lincolne etc, Amstelodami, Sumptibus Henrici Hondii, 1632; (19.5 x 23.25 | tinted and decorated) (165 (Map Case Drawer 14))
    — Text in French on verso: "Description des pays inondes, appellees The Fenne... "
  - The City of London in the Time of the Saxons (about the year 1000), compiled from the most authentic documents, London, J. & E. Wallis, 1817; (21.75 x 24 | black and white) (166 (Map Case Drawer 14))
  - Map of the County of Devon from an actual survey made in the years 1825 & 1826, by C. & J. Greenwood, 1829; (25.5 x 30 | tinted; mounted on cloth) (216 (Map Case Drawer 16))
    — Inset: Lundy Island, upper left; View of Exeter Cathedral, lower right.
  - Map of the County of Rutland from and actual survey made in the year 1825, by C. & J. Greenwood, 1831; (25.5 x 31 | tinted) (217 (Map Case Drawer 16))
    — View of Burley House in lower left.
  - A New Map of Ireland, drawn from the survey made by [Dr. William Petty]..., Sold by [Robert Morden] at the Atlas in Corn-hill..., undated; (24.5 x 38 | tinted; folded) (218 (Map Case Drawer 16))
    — Inset: British Isles.
  - Cambridgeshire, undated; (4 x 6.25 | black and white) (227 (Box 2))
    — Text in English on verso: "Cambridge-shire Chapter XVIII."
  - Devonshire, undated; (4 x 6.25 | black and white) (228 (Box 2))
    — Text on verso: "Devonshire. Chapter IX... "
  - L'Escosse, suivant les dernieres Relations, Par N. Sanson, undated; (7 x 8 | black and white) (229 (Box 2))
  - Devonshire, by John Cary engraver, London, J. cary, 1793; (9.25 x 12 | black and white) (248 (Box 1))
  - Devonshire, by J. & C. Walker,London, Longman, Orme, Rees & Co., 1836; (13.5 x 16.25 | tinted) (249 (Box 1))
  - Rutlandshire, by John Cary engraver, London, J. Cary, 1793; (9 x 12 | tinted) (250 (Box 1))
  - Saxon England according to the Saxon Chronicles, W. H. Toms, sculp, undated; (10.75 x 17 | black and white) (251 (Box 1))
    — Place-names in Old English.
  - A New Description of the Shyres Lothian and Linlithgo, by Timothy Pont. W. & [Joan Blaeu], 1654; (14.5 x 21 | handcolored) (280 (Map Case Drawer 15))
    — Originally published in the Mercator/Hondius Atlas of 1630.
    — Text in French on verso.
  - Hantshire Described and Divided, John Speed. London, 1676; (15 x 20 | handcolored) (284 (Map Case Drawer 15))
    — Engraved by Jodocus Hondius, Amsterdam. Published by Thomas Bassett and Richard Chiswell, London.
    — Text in English on verso.
- MAPS — EUROPE — HUNGARY
  - Novissima et accuratissima totius Hungariae tabula, par P. Du Val... Amsterdam, Gedruckt by [Justus Danckerts, 1635-1701], undated; (20.5 x 24 | tinted and decorated) (167 (Map Case Drawer 14))
  - Maps from Johann van der Bruggen's Tabvla XIII. Repraesentantes Regnum Hungariae, cum adjancentibus Provinciis and Tabvlae IX. Repraesentantes Regna et Provinciae Haereditarias Caesareas, Avgvstae Vindel, excudit Johannes Andreas Pfeffel S. Caes. Maj. Chalcographus, undated; (12.75 x 16.25 | 23 pages sewn together) (168 (Box 1))
- MAPS — EUROPE — ITALY
  - Pianta del Cratere, tra Napoli e Cuma, undated; (14.25 x 19) (054 (Map Case Drawer 13))
  - Pianta Litorale sue adiacenzae, da confini dl Regno di Napoli fin a Pesto, undated (055 (Map Case Drawer 13))
    — Map of Italian coast near Naples and Salerno.
  - Pianta topographica della citta di Napoli in Campagna Felice, Napoli, Presso Nic. Gervasi, undated; (14.5 x 19.75) (056 (Map Case Drawer 13))
  - Territorro Cremasco, undated; (12.5 x 22.25 | tinted) (057 (Map Case Drawer 13))
    — Text on verso (page 69-70): "Territorivm Cremense... "
  - Italy (southern part), by A.K. Johnson, Edinbugh & Glasgow, undated; (21.5 x 26 | colored boundary lines and title shield) (169 (Map Case Drawer 14))
  - Karstia, Carniola, et Windorum Marchia..., per Gerardum Mercatorem, undated; (19 x 23 | Colored boundary lines and title shield) (170 (Map Case Drawer 14))
    — Text in French on verso: "La Karstie... "
  - Status ecclesiasticus et magnus ducatus Thoscanae, per [Frederik de Wit, 1629 or 1630-1706], undated; (20.25 x 25 | tinted) (171 (Map Case Drawer 15))
  - Status et Ducatus Mediolanensis Reipublicae Genuensis et Ducatus Parmensis et Montisferrati, novissima descriptio per [Frederik de Wit, 1629 or 1630-1706] Amstelodami, undated; (20 x 24.5 | colored boundary lines; decorated) (172 (Map Case Drawer 15))
  - Status Reipublicae Genuensis nec non Prospectuum celeberrimae ejusdem Urbis et Portus.. ., Aucthore Ioh Baptista Hohmanno [Johann Baptist Homann, 1663-1724], Norimbergae, undated; (21.25 x 24.25 | tinted) (173 (Map Case Drawer 15))
  - Neapolis Regnum, Matthew Seutteri [Matthäus Seutter, 1678-1757], undated; (8 x 10 | tinted) (174 (Box 2))
  - Dominum Venetum.. ., a [Matthäus Seutter, 1678-1757]... Conr. Lotter, Augsburg, undated; (8 x 10 | tinted) (175 (Box 2))
  - Tabula Europae VI, 1545; (12.25 x 15.75 | black and white) (176 (Box 1))
    — Text on verso: "Italia... "
  - Belli typvs in Italia... in Statv Mediolanesnsi et Dvcatv Mantvae..., per Io. Bapt. Homannvm [Johann Baptist Homann, 1663-1724], 1702; (20.5 x 23.5 | tinted) (177 (Map Case Drawer 15))
  - Statvs Parmensis siv Ducatus Parmensis et Placen Tinus una cum Ditione Buxetana et Valle Tarae.. ., ab Homannianis Heredibvs, 1731; (20.5 x 24.5 | tinted, with insets and decoration in black and white) (178 (Map Case Drawer 15))
  - Mayland, die Haupt — Stadt des Herzogthumbs.. ., edirt und zu finden in der Homännischen Officin, Pianta del Castello di Milano…, 1734; (21 x 24.5 | tinted) (179 (Map Case Drawer 15))
    — Pianta del Castello di Milano 15 Dec. 1733 is the central feature.
    — 8 insets of fortifications around the margins.
  - Plan of Ancient Rome, by W.B. Clarke, architect [London] Published under the superintendence of the Society for the diffusion of Useful Knowledge, 1830; (13 x 16.25 | tinted) (253 (Box 1))
  - A map of Italy..., undated; (16 x 20 | black and white) (MISSING AS OF 2019)
    — One of 10 pages of illustrations made for Tyndal's continuation of Rapin's History of England.
- MAPS — EUROPE — LITHUANIA
  - Magni Ducatus Lithuaniae, undated; (19.5 x 22.75 | tinted) (058 (Map Case Drawer 13))
    — Text in French on verso: "La Samogitie" and "La Litvanie."
- MAPS — EUROPE — LUXEMBOURG
  - Lvtzenbvrgen.. ., Iacobo Surhonio Montano auctore, undated; (17 x 22 | tinted) (059 (Map Case Drawer 13))
    — Text in Latin on verso (p.26). "Lvtzenbvrgvm Dvcatvs."
    — In pencil on verso: "1555?"
  - Lutzenburg ducatus, Amsterdami, apud Guiljelmum et Ioannem Blaeu [Willem (Janszoon?) Blaeu and Joan Blaeu], undated; (20 x 24 | tinted) (116 (Map Case Drawer 14))
    — Text on verso (pages 23-24).
- MAPS — EUROPE — NETHERLANDS
  - Rhinolandiae, Amstelandiae, et circumiacent..., Auct. Balthazaro Flor. A Berckenrode. Amsterdam, Frederick de Wit, 1667; (19 x 23 | black and white) (061 (Map Case Drawer 13))
  - Agri Biemstrani descriptio a L.I.S., undated; (20 x 24 | tinted) (120 (Map Case Drawer 14))
    — Showing polders, canals and villages, including Schermerhorn on the Schermer.
    — Text on verso (pages 51-52).
  - Clivia ducatus et Ravenstein dominium, undated; (20 x 24 | tinted) (121 (Map Case Drawer 14))
    — Ravenstein, showing Nimmegen toward the upper left.
    — Text on verso (pages 249-250).
  - Geldria ducatus, et Zutfania comitatus, Amsterda Apud Guilj. Blaeuw [Willem (Janszoon?) Blaeu], undated; (20 x 24 | tinted) (122 (Map Case Drawer 14))
    — Text on verso (pages 1-2).
    — Gederland. Geldern, a ducal capital, the Netherlands.
  - United Provinces, or Netherlands.. ., History of England, By Herman Moll, South Britain. London: Printed and Sold by Ino. Bowles.. ., 1728; (24.5 x 41.5 | tinted) (123 (Map Case Drawer 13))
    — 2 maps attached to each other (4 pages).
    — Insets: (1) Chart of North Sea and several city views; (2) Coats of Arms and list of cities.
  - Tabula Bergarum ad Zomam Stenbergae et novorum ibi operum, Ad amussim fecit Francisco van Schoten Math. Professor in Acad. Leidensi. Exc. Guiljelmus Blaeuw [Willem (Janszoon?) Blaeu], (20 x 23 | tinted) (180 (Map Case Drawer 15))
    — Text on verso (pages 83-84).
    — Bergen and Steenbergen.
  - Territorium Bergense, undated; (20 x 24 | tinted and decorated) (181 (Map Case Drawer 15))
    — Text in Latin on verso: "Castellania Bergensis" (pages 99-100).
  - Ultraiectum Dominum, excudit Guiljelmus Blaeuw [Willem (Janszoon?) Blaeu], City of Utrecht, undated; (20 x 24 | tinted and decorated) (182 (Map Case Drawer 15))
    — Text in Latin on verso (pages 65-66): "Vltraiectinvm Dominivm."
  - Walachria, Zelandiae Cisscaldinae insula occidentalis, undated; (20 x 24 | tinted) (183 (Map Case Drawer 15))
    — Text on verso (pages 59-60).
  - ... Zelandiae Cisscaldinae..., islands near the East Scheldt, undated; (20 x 24 | tinted) (184 (Map Case Drawer 15))
    — Text on verso (pages 61-62).
  - Zvydhollandia stricte sumta, Amsterdami, Guiljelmus Blaeu [Blaeu, Willem (Janszoon?)] excudit, undated; (20 x 24 | tinted) (185 (Map Case Drawer 15))
    — Text in Latin on verso (pages 35-36): "Hollandia Avstralia."
  - Battle of Maestricht... May 14th, 1703, undated; (16 x 20 | black and white) (MISSING AS OF 2019)
    — One of 10 pages of illustrations for Tyndal's continuation of Rapin's History of England.
  - A new and correct map of the Netherlands..., by [Emanuel Bowen, 1693 or 1694-1767], undated; (16 x 19 | black and white) (MISSING AS OF 2019)
- MAPS — EUROPE — PORTUGAL
  - Portugalliae et Algarbiae.. ., a Ioanne Bapt Homanno [Johann Baptist Homann, 1663-1724], Nirimberg, undated; (20.25 x 24 | tinted and decorated) (188 (Map Case Drawer 15))
    — Inset: portion of Brazil.
- MAPS — EUROPE — RUSSIA
  - Moscovey in Europe, from the latest observations, humbly inscribed to Abel Ketelbey of the Inner Temple Esq. By I Senex, undated; (21 x 25 | colored boundary lines) (189 (Map Case Drawer 15))
  - A new map of the Russian Empire.. ., by J. Cary, engraver. London: J. Cary, 1811; (19.25 x 23.25 | tinted) (190 (Map Case Drawer 15))
    — 2 separate but contiguous maps; part of title appears on each one.
- MAPS — EUROPE — SPAIN
  - Tabula Evropae II, 1552; (12.25 x 15.75 | black and white) (272 (Box 1))
    — Text on verso: "Hispania... "
  - Oporto, [London] Pub. under the superintendence of the Society for the Diffusion of Useful Knowledge, 1833; (13 x 16 | tinted) (273 (Box 1))
    — City plans with engraved view added.
  - Plan of the City and the Castle of Alicant, besieged by the Chevalier d' Asfeldt Nov. 30th 1708, undated; (16 x 20 | black and white) (MISSING AS OF 2019)
  - Plan of the City of Barcelona, undated; (16 x 20 | black and white) (MISSING AS OF 2019)
- MAPS — EUROPE — SWITZERLAND
  - Helvetia..., Describebat Gerard Mercator, et excudebat Guiljelmus Blaeu [Willem (Janszoon?) Blaeu], undated; (19 x 24.5 | tinted) (194 (Map Case Drawer 15))
    — With 3 attached, unnumbered, pages of text from the atlas: "Svngovia, Brisgoia, Helvetia... "
  - ... Helvetiae, Rhaetiae, Valesiae et partis Sabaudia tabula, ex officiana Iusti Danckerts [Justus Danckerts, 1635-1701], [Amsterdam]..., undated; (20.75 x 24 | tinted; 2 copies, each colored differently) (195-196 (Map Case Drawer 15))
  - Carte de la Suisse.. ., publiee par Francois Grasset... a Lausanne, 1769. Supervised by M. Robert de Vaugonfy, undated; (21 x 27.5 | colored boundaries) (197 (Map Case Drawer 15))
- MAPS — MEXICO
  - Mexico or New Spain in which the Motions of Cortes may be traced, for the Rev Dr. Robertson's History of America, by Thomas Kitchin Senior, W. Strahan and T. Cadell, Sept 29, 1777, undated; (12 x 16 | tinted) (254 (Box 1))
    — Pencil note: "modern color."
- MAPS — NEAR EAST
  - A new and accurate map of Turkey in Asia, Arabia etc., by [Emanuel Bowen, 1693 or 1694-1767], undated; (16 x 19.25 | black and white; decorated) (060 (Map Case Drawer 13))
- MAPS — NORTH AMERICA
  - An accurate map of North America describing and distinguishing the British and Spanish dominions... according to the definitive treaty concluded at Paris 10th Feb. 1763..., by [Emanuel Bowen, 1693 or 1694-1767]... and John Gibson..., undated; (21.5 x 57.5 | tinted boundary lines; edges in poor condition; in 2 pieces) (062 (Map Case Drawer 13))
    — Inset: Baffin and Hudson's Bay. With articles from the treaty printed in ocean areas.
  - Carte des parties nord et ouest de L'Amerique dressée d'aprés les relations les plus authentiques.., Nouvelle édition réduite par M. de Vougondy en, 1772; (15.5 x 18 | black and white) (063 (Map Case Drawer 13))
    — Shows Indian tribes.
  - Nouvelle Carte Particuliere de l' Amerique, ou sont exactement marquees les Provinces suivant comme la Caroline Meridionale, la Floride... A Map of the British Empire in America..., by Henry Popple, at Amsterdam, printed for Iohn Covens and Corneius Mortier, undated (186 (Map Case Drawer 15))
  - To the Right Honourable John Lord Sommers... this map of North America... is most humbly dedicated by... Herman Mill..., [London], undated; (24.5 x 40.5 | tinted and decorated; folded; margins in poor condition) (219 (Map Case Drawer 16))
    — Insets: drying cod in New Found Land; and several ports and harbours..
  - North America, 1776; (8.25 x 10.25 | black and white) (231 (Box 2))
  - Cette carte de Californie et Du Nouveau Mexique, par N. de Fer, 1705; (10 x 14.25 | black and white) (255 (Box 1))
  - A New Map of ye North Parts of America Claimed by France under ye names of Louisiana, Mississippi, Canada, & New France, with the Adjoyning Territories of England and Spain, By Herman Moll Geographer, 1730; (9.25 x 14 | black and white) (256 (Box 1))
  - A Map of the British Plantations on the Continent of America, 1739; (13.75 x 12 | black and white) (257 (Box 1))
  - America del Norte, J. Barthelemier, undated; (9.5 x 12 | black and white) (258 (Box 1))
  - Insulae Americanae in Oceano Septentrionali ac Regiones Adiacentes.. ., Nicholas Visscher. Amsterdam, approximately 1680; (8.25 x 22 | handcolored) (287 (Map Case Drawer 16))
- MAPS — PACIFIC OCEAN
  - Carte de la partie septentrionale de la Mer du Sud... tiree de la Carte Generale Angloise des decouvertes de Captaine Cook, Grave par Dupuis, undated; (12.25 x 18 | black and white) (064 (Map Case Drawer 13))
    — Northern Pacific Ocean with adjoining coasts.
  - A map of the discoveries made by Captains Cook & Clerke in the Years 1778 & 1779 between the Eastern Coast of Asia and the Western Coast of North America when they attempted to Navigate the North Sea..., 1795; (15 x 18 | black and white) (065 (Map Case Drawer 13))
    — Engraved for Carey's America edition of Guthrie's Geography improved.
  - The Russian discoveries from the map published by the Imperial Academy of St. Petersburg,, London, Printed for Robert Sayer, 1775; (21.5 x 29.25 | colored boundary lines) (187 (Map Case Drawer 15))
    — Northeastern Asia and Northwestern North America.
- MAPS — POLAR REGIONS
  - Nieuwe Kaart van de Noord Pool..., Amsterdam, door Isaak Tirion, 1735; (16 x 18.5 | tinted) (066 (Map Case Drawer 13))
    — Northern hemisphere with North Pole at center.
- MAPS — ROMAN EMPIRE
  - Romani Imperii Imago, undated; (19 x 22 | black and white) (067 (Map Case Drawer 13))
    — Text in pencil on verso (page vii): "Ortelius 1612."
  - Orbis Romani Par Occidentalis..., [London] Drawn & engraved for J. Harrison, 1790; (17.5 x 21 | black and white) (068 (Map Case Drawer 13))
- MAPS — SOLAR SYSTEM